Andrea Amorosi



 Viale della Repubblica 28, Cecina, 57023, Italy

+39 347 8087387

dreamorosi@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/dreamorosi

Profile



A recent 24 years old graduate in Humanities Computing at Università di Pisa, with proven experience in the web development field thanks to 2+ years of freelancing and collaborations with several agencies. Specialises in creating modern and rich web applications through attention to details, compliance with web standards and strong problem solving skills. Now seeking to transition in the User Experience in order to put to good use his craft and skills to build meaningful experiences.

Experience



Front end developer, Pino Inside; Viareggio, IT – 2013-2014

During this first part-time job I had the opportunity to learn what it means to work in a team. While generally being a good team player I never shied to emerge as leader when the situation required it and, most importantly, to actively parcticipate in the decisional process. In this period I worked mainly on websites for small to medium businesses and also on graphic and logo design

Full stack developer, Yellow Unicorns; Milan, IT - 2015-2016

In this six month collaboration I finally had the chance to expand my portfolio by working on a public institution's project. Working with a small team of four people I participated at the creation of an online portal for the assignment of government funds to local businesses aimed at improving safety on the workplaces. I mainly worked on the MVC structure of the platform and on the backend section but I also curated its front end layout and homepage.

Full stack developer, Freelance - 2014-present

In the last two years and half I've worked as freelancer using the online platform <u>Upwork</u> in a number of different projects, ranging from edits on existing platforms to creation of brand new websites and web applications. During this time I had the chance to improve my way of communicating with clients, understand the different stakes in a project, manage deadlines and last but not least learn countless lessons that make the professional I am today.

Education



Technical Toolbox



Università di Pisa; Pisa, IT - Bachelor Degree in Humanities Computing, 2016 University of Reading; Reading, UK - Exchange year with Erasmus+ programme, 2014

Proficient in JavaScript, PHP, HTML, CSS, XML; Intermediate knowledge in Node.js and Python

Skilled in Adobe Photoshop, Abobe Illustrator and Sketch.

Experienced in using all kinds of web API, REST and XML; <u>Foundation</u> and <u>Bootstrap</u>; <u>React.js</u> and <u>jQuery</u>.